Guide to the Basin (Mont.) Post Office records 1899-1931
Montana Historical Society
Basin Post Office records
1899-1931
Montana Historical Society Archives
MC 225
Basin Post Office (Basin, Mont.)
2.2 linear feet
Records of the Basin, Montana, post office include cash books (1902-1917); postmaster's account and record books (1900-1917); registers (1899-1916, 1923-1931) of money orders issued and received; register (1905-1919) of notices to publishers of removed and unknown addressees; registered mail receipts (1908-1922); and stamp impression books (1905-1910, 1917).
Basin, Montana, was established in 1880 as a gold mining town on the site of the former town of Cataract. The post office was established in 1880 and has operated continuously ever since.
Records (1899-1931) include cash books (1902-1917); postmaster's account and record books (1900-1917); registers (1899-1916, 1923-1931) of money orders issued and received; register (1905-1919) of notices to publishers of removed and unknown addressees; registered mail receipts (1908-1922); and stamp impression books (1905-1910, 1917).
Arranged by series: Incoming Correspondence, Financial Records, and Miscellany.
Collection open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Basin Post Office (Basin, Mont.)
Basin (Mont.)
Postal service
Montana
Detailed Description of the Collection
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection
- Incoming Correspondence
  - Circular letters, 1917 (Box-folder 1 / 1)
- Financial Records
  - Cash book: District Post Office, 1924 January-December (Box-folder 1 / 2)
  - Cash book of the International Money Order Office, 1902 March - 1914 December (Box-folder 1 / 3-7)
  - Cash book of the International Money Order Office, 1914 December - 1917 September (Box-folder 2 / 1)
  - Postmaster's account and record book, 1900 October - 1917 December (Box-folder 2 / 2-10)
  - Receipts for newspaper and periodical postage collected, 1906 February - 1910 October (Box-folder 3 / 1)
  - Receipts for special delivery mail, 1921, 1925 (Box-folder 3 / 2)
  - Register of money order advices received, 1899 July - 1908 November (Box-folder 3 / 3)
  - Register of money orders issued, 1906 January - 1916 January (Box-folder 3 / 4-6)
  - Register of money orders issued, 1923 May - 1931 March (Box-folder 4 / 1-6)
- Miscellany
  - Record of notices to publishers (re refused mail and moved or unknown addressees), 1905-1919 (Box-folder 4 / 7)
  - Record of registered matter in transit, 1907-1923 (Box-folder 5 / 1)
  - Registered mail receipt book, 1908 August - 1910 July (Box-folder 5 / 2-3)
  - Registered matter received and delivered, 1914 July - 1922 January (Box-folder 5 / 4-5)
  - Stamp impression book (postmarks), 1905-1910, 1917 (Box-folder 5 / 6-7)
  - Miscellaneous (includes instructions to district postmaster), 1907, 1917 (Box-folder 5 / 8)